♪ As I step down from the train ♪
♪ And there to meet me is
my mama and papa ♪
♪ And down the road I
look and there runs... ♪
We're closed.
♪ Hair of gold and lips like cherries... ♪
Sir...
You OK?
Useless!
Hey, babe?
- Is something wrong?
- No.
Is everything OK?
No, it's fine. Um...
It's just been a while
since I've been back home.
OK.
Yeah, I mean, I can...
I can take time off and...
maybe finally meet your family.
No, it's... it's all right.
There's just some stuff
I gotta deal with.
On my own.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
I promise.
OK.
I still wanna
meet your brother.
I'd like that too.
Hold still.
How do I look?
Pretty.
Where did you put your glasses?
Are you sleeping
with them on again?
You know...
you need these to see...
my beautiful face.
You wanna go wash up?
- OK.
- And get ready?
Morning, Auntie.
Mind making Gracie's lunch?
Mm.
I'm late. Can you make sure...
I'll make sure
she gets to school. Clean.
Thank you.
Wanna grab a coffee?
Big brother.
Come in.
Keep watching that screen and
your eyeballs will fall out.
Who are you?
I'm your relative. Mise'l.
He's your uncle.
Uncle.
Come say hi.
Hi. I got this for you.
What do you say?
- Thank you.
- Hey.
- Wanna pick out a bedtime story?
- OK.
Remember to brush your teeth,
OK?
- Sit.
- Thank you.
She's huge.
Yeah. Yeah, she is.
Where's Nsukwis Malia'n?
Oh, it's bingo night.
Is, um... Bobby with you?
Barry.
No, it's just me.
So, what brought you
all the way out here?
You OK?
I saw him.
I stopped by the old house
on the way over.
Whole area is clear-cut.
They're gutting the forest.
If they make it to the cave...
We both swore we'd never...
talk about this.
If he can get to me in the city,
he's already at your backdoor.
We go in there...
we take care of him,
and we can both get back
to our own lives.
No.
It's done.
He's... gone.
We both just...
need to let this go.
He's not letting
either of us go.
I can't carry it alone.
Holy Mary.
- I must be seeing things.
- Hello, Auntie.
Not been home in 20 years.
It hasn't been that long.
Missed five funerals, barely
call or send a text message...
And now you appear
just like that.
I'm sorry.
Nothing to be afraid of.
We're family.
It's good to see you, kwis.
Even if you are
an ungrateful brat.
If you'd called ahead,
I could've cleaned out
the spare room for you.
I'm not staying long.
Dad, can I go and play outside?
You can,
but stay out of the dirt.
Don't expect me
to go out of my way
to entertain you
while you're here.
Actually, I'm going camping
in the Old Forest.
Hello?
No, I told you.
Don't listen to her...
What are you doing?
You know
you can't go in there alone.
Someone has to.
What? No...
Antle?
What's she doing?
Grace!
You all right?
You have to aim.
What?
He said you have to aim.
- Go back inside.
- But I want to play out here.
See if you can find that song
on YouTube for me.
You never went back to
the woods after all these years?
Did you?
- George?
- Yeah?
You noticed anything different
here lately?
Chief and Counsel were
asking me the same thing.
Have you seen anything?
We're looking for a cave
deep in the old forest
with petroglyphs
carved into the entrance.
Hm.
Wait here.
Oh, Natalie printed those off
for me.
That's your
great-great-grandfather.
Old Holy Joe,
they called him...
because he wore
a big, hand-carved cross.
The way up here is blocked.
A windstorm knocked down
some trees.
Best to follow the river.
Oof.
I've kept this for you.
A medicine bundle,
for your journey.
Thanks.
The forest will reveal
the rest.
Hm.
Thanks, guys.
We should go.
Thank you, Elder.
So, you're a healer now?
Mess off!
Fine. Keep all that shit
to yourself, then.
Shit!
You all right?
Let's get this shit over with.
Long ago, before disruption,
the forest was
our first teacher.
It gave us everything
we needed.
The people and the land are
forever related.
When the land is in pain,
so are we.
In difficult times, we return
to the heart of the forest.
We return to learn,
and to be given
what is needed to heal.
You got it going.
We should stop here.
The faster we get there,
the faster we get back.
- Keep paddling.
- We're stopping!
Help me find a place to land.
Let's find a spot over there.
Antle!
Antle?
I got you.
We're safe.
It won't come now.
He was chasing us again.
He wanted me to hold down Andy
while he used the belt on him.
I remember.
What happens?
After this?
We survive.
So...
the canoe's gone.
What's your big plan now?
We're gonna walk the rest.
- We're lost.
- We'll follow the river.
'Follow the river.'
Assuming ghouls don't travel
on land too, of course.
Grace will be fine.
How do you know that?
Nsukwis has got her.
Don't act like you suddenly
give a shit about my life.
All right?
What the fuck?
Antle!
Back away into the water...
...slowly.
Keep going, don't stop!
You manage to salvage anything?
Nope.
Now everything's soaked again.
Leech.
Remember when you fell
in a nest of leeches?
What?
The leech thing.
They were everywhere.
It was like a wiggling...
Mise'l!
I'm just saying,
maybe this is then.
It's just a worm.
Pull back like this...
then let go.
If I catch a fish,
- can you clean it?
- Nope.
That's your job.
- But I'll help you.
- OK.
I saw you and Trevor
behind the house yesterday.
- What?
- You kissed him.
- You're hurting me!
- Tell no one.
- Let go!
- I'm serious.
Swear to me you won't tell him.
Antle!
Will you help me gut my fish?
You gotta catch one first,
dummy.
Why were you kissing Trevor?
His sister likes you.
And I like Trevor.
Come on.
Hurry up or he'll be pissed!
♪ Down the road I look
and there runs Mary ♪
♪ Hair of gold and
lips like cherries ♪
♪ It's good to touch the
green, green grass of home ♪
♪ Yes, they'll all come
to meet me ♪
♪ Arms reaching, smiling sweetly ♪
♪ It's so good to touch... ♪
No, Mise'l!
You know, I remember that day.
Always jealous of your bike.
The pink monster I inherited
from Cousin Dawn?
It had brakes
on the handle bars.
Yeah.
I got the shit kicked out of me
at least three times.
It had a bell too.
I don't know
why I can't be like that...
that kid anymore.
You know?
Yeah.
I know.
Push!
Do you speak our language?
We speak it.
I'm Mise'l.
This is my brother.
- His name is Antle.
- Mm.
I'm Holy Joe.
I was praying for help.
Looks like the Lord sent you.
Can you lend a hand?
We'll rest after, have a meal.
You're both welcome to join.
Thank you.
Push!
Push, push!
Hey!
Good job, kwis.
Bless us, O Lord,
and the gifts we are about
to receive from Thy bounty,
through Christ our Lord.
Amen.
Can't say I've seen
this cave of yours.
This place is tricky.
Been using these roads
for the past 20 years now.
Seen all sorts of things.
I don't know how to find it,
but I know someone
who can guide you.
Head west.
A healer lives there.
Deep up in them hills.
You go past the river,
about a day or two.
Look for the doorway.
Sometimes it takes one spirit
to fight another.
Lord protect you.
We're heading out
first thing in the morning.
Eat. Rest.
Pray.
Begone, spirit!
Ju'kwa'tik nuluksk.
Come, my nephews.
Ke wi'je'wi.
Walk with me.
Wel-jesi-oq te't.
You're safe here.
Te't na naka'si'te'sk
t'et klapis...
This is where my
path one day ends.
Kilo nasik si'eow wa'sioq...
But your path continues.
Amu'jpa ma'ja'sioq
aqq kesalulo'q
It's time for you to go.
Antle!
Let's rest a minute.
I remember when I was the one
who used to help you up.
Job keeps you in shape.
Never know when you need
to carry a 200-pound guy.
I am not a guy.
Or 200 pounds.
201. Sorry.
Grace seems pretty happy.
Probably not easy
raising a kid alone.
Nsukwis helps.
Still, it's hard.
Explains why you never got out.
What the hell is
that supposed to mean?
Do you really wanna stay here?
You've got your life
in the city.
I've got mine here.
What about Grace?
What kind of life
will she have?
I got my shit together,
all right.
I'm not some weak little f...
Wait.
Mise'l?
Calm down.
Listen to me.
It'll be fine, don't cry.
It's OK. You're OK.
We won't tell anyone,
I promise.
You didn't do anything wrong.
I'm sorry.
About earlier.
I don't think that about you.
Come on. This way.
No respect for property.
Help! Fire, fire!
Fuck!
Antle!
I knew I heard something.
- Indian?
- Half-breed maybe?
All these savages
dress strange.
Ha! Let's bring him in.
Better to scalp him.
Ten whole Guineas.
Come, help me!
- You're Mi'kmaw?
- Yes.
Are you spirits?
We're safe here for now.
They couldn't find their nose
in front of their face.
My brother is sick.
Whatever made you sick
is eating you from the inside.
You too.
We're looking for a healer.
It's too risky.
They look strange,
but they are like us.
We can't abandon them.
Just tell us where to go.
I'll take you.
Hey.
No, I can't lose you.
I'll be quick.
I can't take you all the way,
just past the battlefield.
Thank you.
Come on!
Let's go.
Keep heading west.
Follow the river.
She'll find you.
We'll meet again.
Probably not even out there.
Hear that?
Come back this way.
Antle!
Maybe something...
Maybe something in here
will help.
You promised
everything would be OK.
Long have I waited.
It's been so long
since I've seen you both.
Welcome, Father.
Gracie?
Don't mind them.
We're safe here.
How long have you been here?
This is the place of spirits.
Time is unfixed.
You'll need this
for what's to come.
We won't come back, will we?
In my season of time,
you never return.
They're coming.
Don't look back, don't stop.
Don't look back.
I know what you intend to do.
But this...
you can't stop it.
Wkamlamun.
It's the heart.
The place where you're going,
there's a large lake nearby.
Carved by glaciers,
thousands of times.
Return him to the land there.
I've prepared the way.
Come with us.
When it's all over,
we can go home.
- All together.
- Mm.
All of us.
You have to go now,
or you'll miss it.
You're so beautiful.
Come home this time.
Mise'l.
I can't.
♪ As I step down from the train ♪
♪ And there to meet me is
my mama and papa ♪
♪ Down the road I look
and there runs Mary ♪
♪ Hair of gold and
lips like cherries ♪
♪ It's good to touch the
green, green grass of home ♪
♪ Yes, they'll all come to meet me ♪
♪ Arms reaching, smiling sweetly ♪
♪ It's so good to touch the
green, green grass of home ♪
♪ The old house is still standing ♪
♪ Though the paint... ♪
♪ ...The green, green grass ♪
Get out.
Get my gun.
Not you.
My son.
Come here.
Don't drop it, you little shit.
Barrel.
Butt.
Trigger.
You aim this
at what needs shooting,
breathe out...
and squeeze gently.
You understand?
Aim at the bottle.
Breathe out.
And squeeze.
Walk.
Walk, boy.
And don't look back.
We're gonna play a little game.
Shoot the fruit.
Remember.
Aim...
breathe out and squeeze.
- But...
- Do it!
Do. It.
Do it.
- Do it!
- No!
Oh, shit!
You shot him!
Come with me.
Little bro.
You ready for what's next?
Take him to the river.
Where's... the skull?
I'll go.
Aim.
Breathe...
out.
Do it.
Squeeze.
Please.
Do it!
I know...
it's hard for you...
to be around me.
It's true.
I knew it the day
you left me behind
for the big city.
No, brother.
I left because...
every time you looked at me...
all I saw was pain...
and guilt.
I didn't want that
to be your life.
Leaving... didn't change that.
I wish we both could be different,
everything could be different.
I knew you'd come home.
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Walk with me ♪
♪ Together you and I ♪
♪ Always remember ♪
♪ Sweetheart ♪
♪ I will always be there for you ♪
♪ Weya heya, heya heyo ♪
♪ I would walk through the night ♪
♪ Across the land to sea ♪
♪ And see you standing there ♪
♪ In new light ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Walk with me ♪
♪ Into new love ♪
♪ New love ♪
♪ Where we've been waiting ♪
♪ Working towards our new love ♪
♪ New love ♪
♪ Oh will you wait ♪
♪ Or walk with me? ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ And try to see ♪
♪ Cross rivers that you've feared ♪
♪ Stories you're afraid to hear ♪
♪ Can't keep our love away ♪
♪ I will always be there for you ♪
♪ When you feel all this grief ♪
♪ When your tears find you again ♪
♪ When your heart asks who's there ♪
♪ Dreams still whispering ♪
♪ Until we start to sing again ♪
♪ Weya heya, heya heyo ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ But not my light ♪
♪ The words that we find are new ♪
♪ And all of the ghosts ♪
♪ That we sing back to ♪
♪ Teach us our way of listening ♪
♪ Give yourself to dancing days ♪
♪ Sorrow and grief create a place ♪
♪ For new love to enter ♪
♪ If you listen for its name ♪
♪ I will always be there for you ♪
♪ In new love ♪
♪ New love ♪
♪ Where we've been waiting ♪
♪ Walking towards ♪
♪ New love ♪
♪ Oh, will you wait ♪
♪ Or walk with me? ♪
♪ Take my hand ♪
♪ Walk with me ♪
♪ Together you and I ♪
♪ Always remember ♪
♪ Sweetheart ♪
♪ I will always be there for you ♪
♪ Weya heya, heya heyo ♪♪